Joseph Kochevar

Mailing Address: 13764 NE 12th ST APT J201 Bellevue, WA 98005

Last Updated on 26th August 2019

SUMMARY OF QUALIFICATIONS

Early- to Mid- career mechanical engineer with a strong background in mechanical design, large assembly management, drafting, and structural analysis. Possesses multidisciplinary industry-level engineering experience and a demonstrated ability to perform in a multitude of roles with high levels of success.

EDUCATION

OLIN COLLEGE

BS IN MECHANICAL ENGINEERING May 2016 | Needham, MA

Recipient of 4-year, 50% Olin Merit Scholarship Conc. in Entrepreneurship Cum. GPA: 3.75 / 4.0

COURSEWORK

ENGINEERING

Principles of Engineering†
Mechanical Design
Thermodynamics†
Microfluidics
Mechanical and Aerospace Systems
Design For Manufacturing

ENTREPRENEURSHIP

The Entrepreneurial Initiative New Technology Ventures Intellectual Property and Patent Law (†: Returned as Course Assistant)

SKILLS

MECHANICAL

PTC Creo • Windchill • Ansys Solidworks • Solidworks PDM AutoDesk Inventor • AutoCAD

SOFTWARE

MATLAB • COMSOL • Arduino Java • C • C++ • HTML • Python

FABRICATION

Mill • Lathe • CNC • Laser Cutter Waterjet • 3d Printing • Vinyl Cutter Pneumatic Tools • Tube Bending MIG Welding • Brazing

EXPERIENCE

BLUE ORIGIN | PROPULSION ENGINEER II

June 2016 - Present | Kent, WA

- Responsible engineer for majority of BE-4 engine ancillary systems and secondary structure
- Configured multiple unique development engine builds to accommodate development and qualification testing
- Analyzed and released hundreds of drawings for development, qualification, and flight
- Worked with external and internal customers to accommodate vehicle needs and manage system interfaces.
- Designed laser optics and purge tooling for custom manufacturing systems.

SENIOR CAPSTONE: BOEING | MECHANICAL ENGINEER Sept 2015 - May 2016 | Needham, MA

- Optimized 737 final manufacturing to improve cargo bay panel installation.
- Also acting as business manager, organizing budgeting and purchases.

OLIN COLLEGE BLIND SAILING | MECHANICAL ENGINEER

June 2015 – Aug 2015 | Needham, MA

• Led mechanical design to outfit a sailboat with equipment to enable it to be sailed competitively by blind sailors.

PROTEDYNE CORPORATION | MECHANICAL ENGINEERING INTERN June 2014 – Aug 2014 | Windsor, CT

- Assisted in design and modification of large-scale laboratory automation systems.
- Manipulated and created drawings, parts, and assemblies using SolidWorks.

INTUIT: QUICKBASE | PD ENGINEERING INTERN, PRIVATE CONTRACTOR June 2013 – March 2014 | Waltham, MA

- Worked as a full-time engineer on the QuickBase Delight Product engineering team.
- Answered customer feedback, and added features to the automated email system.

ATK AEROSPACE SYSTEMS | ENGINEERING INTERN June 2012 - Aug 2012 | Monterey, CA

• Worked with a team of engineers on UAV sensing payload modules and advanced signal processing.

LEADERSHIP AND ACTIVITIES

OLIN BAJA SAE | TEAM CAPTAIN – DESIGN LEAD Aug 2012 – Present | Needham, MA

- Directed component- and system-level designs for four separate off-road racing vehicles.
- All designs used CAD modeling in SolidWorks, and finite element analysis to meet FS standards.

ROBOTIC GUITAR Oct 2013 - May 2015

 Acted as the mechanical lead in the design and construction of a self-playing guitar system.

CVT TESTING AND TUNING PLATFORM Oct 2012 - June 2016

- Designed and built platform to simulate, test, and tune Continuously Variable Transmissions.
- Created and modified simulations to predict and explain CVT performance.
- Made Olin Baja one of the first and only SAE Baja teams to have a full CVT simulation, testing, and diagnostic tool suite.